Ryan P. Roderick

Web Developer 603-812-9294

Ryan@DesignMonster.com

Camden, Me 04843

https://github.com/RpRoderick https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-roderick https://www.DesignMonster.com

I am a web developer with a history in metal fabrication, forging, and engineering. In 2016 I pursued my goal to work in the field of Technology. Web Development allows me to bring the skills I've learned throughout my fabrication career into a new and exciting territory. My passion for building things and my desire to create has always fueled my choices, and it's this same passion that led me to Development. I have spent the last three years teaching myself how to be a web developer, building side projects, completing an internship, and contributing to open source.

Programming & Computer Skills

- JavaScript HandleBars/HTMLBars Html CSS SASS SCSS Jquery
- ES6+ Ember.js React.js Vue.js Ruby Rails Sql
- Responsive Web Design Cross-browser Compatibility

Work Experience

Web Developer Design Monster, LLC Brookline, NH 02/2017 - Present

- · Work with small businesses and entrepreneurs to make their vision a reality
- Specializes in Ember.js
- Turn ideas into functional products that do exactly what they were designed to do
- Development and consultation work to facilitate emergent technologies and create innovative products

Web Developer Internship TenLegs Brooklyn, NY 06/2017 – 11/2017

- Worked remotely in a collaborative environment with other developers, front and back end, and UX/UI leaders to complete sprints on time and with best coding practices
- Learned best practices in a team environment utilizing such tools as JIRA, KANBAN, GIT (with GitLab), and attended morning meetings (remotely) using AGILE structure
- · Strengthened CSS3, SASS, SCSS, HTML, HBS and JS skills through various tasks
- Focused on Ember.js and front-end responsiveness. Tasks included refactoring components to fit specific client needs, building all new functionality when needed, and restructuring the entire application from a block system to Flexbox

Web Developer In-Training General Assembly Boston, MA 10/2016 – 01/2017

- Designed, planned, documented, and executed four projects from start to finish
- Developed User Stories and implemented UI and UX solutions
- · Reviewed different methodologies of programming, such as Object Oriented Design and Agile Development
- Covered basic IT and CS concepts, along with general software concepts like security, database relationships, and layering.
- · Worked in Bash shell, utilized node.js, npm and bower packages, and learned best practices of Git and GitHub

Shipfitter Metal Fabrication

Portsmouth Naval Shipyard Kittery, ME

02/2014 - 09/2016

- Active member of teams responsible for the on-time redeployment of Nuclear Powered Submarines; duties included engineering, fabrication, and deployment of structural components with teams across every trade
- Successfully completed various duties, tasks, and projects on board U.S. Nuclear Submarines, including but not limited to: fabrication, weld preparation, use of all manner of machinery and design
- Working at the Portsmouth Naval Shipyard introduced me to working on large projects while interacting with numerous smaller groups, each tasked with completing their own parts of a much larger picture. The day to day details of my work varied greatly, ranging from completing small tasks or even just parts of small tasks, to putting the finishing touches on whole projects and signing off on their completion 06/2017-

Process Aptitude & Problem Solving

- Driven to solve problems through application of thoughtful process and attention to reducing wasted energy.
- Applied and utilized the Kaizen system in fabrication jobs and workshop design.
- Cultivated understanding that every small project is an integral part of a profitable venture.
- · Ability and desire to work with teams and independently to deliver on time, fully functioning products.

Engineering & Fabrication Skills

- Well-grounded in a structured approach informed by time constraints and project parameters.
- Mastery of small and large fabrication utilizing welding equipment and techniques, forging, plasma cutting, etc.
- Ability to design, fabricate and install a variety of products for homes, landscapes, and ships.
- Demonstrated facility working independently and collaboratively.
- Dedicated to calculated investigation, persistence and maintained focus to accomplish the job at hand.

Education Experience

FreeCodeCamp Online 2019 – 2020

- Earned Certification in Responsive Web Design (300 hours)
- Earned Certification in Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures (300 hours)
- Earned Certification in Front End Libraries (300 hours)
- Continuously Working Through the Remaining Certifications

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly

Boston, MA

10/2016 - 01/2017

- Certification from General Assembly for full-time thirteen week Web Development Immersive course.
- Project languages include JavaScript, Ruby, Ember, Jquery, Handlebars, Rails, Html, CSS, among others.
- General Assembly is a Massachusetts-Accredited tech training center, based in New York and operating internationally.